Hi, in this lesson I will go you through as the ask mode you need to have a pilot.
I will explain for what type of task you can use, ask mode, what is it, what's the
controls and interfaces are, so let's get started.
Use ask mode, you can find here at the drop-down, you can also switch between different
modes and for every of the small I have separate lessons.
Ask mode, you can use to ask questions about your full code base or some technology
concepts.
It's useful for getting a better understanding of your code basis, brainstorm some ideas,
and getting help with coding tasks.
Now I want to show you some popular use cases, I prepared some nice presentations
slide, with all the use cases, like some popular one and you can base your prompts,
base in this use cases of course.
The first is ask questions about your code base, for example you can ask what does the
use effect in this component do or what does any other hook doing this component or method
like if you don't understand how it works you can always ask a pilot about it.
You can explain how this, for example, solved functionality works or how the filter
in functionality works, it will explain it for you.
You can also brainstorm some ideas, for example you can ask, give me five ideas how to
name this method or this variable or what you can ask, for example what the cases I should
cover for this component, if you don't know all the cases, you just want to start quickly
you can ask a pilot.
If you work with CSS, for example you can ask how to center this model window by the horizontal
and vertical position using CSS, how to add this border or this animation, for example.
I can also ask how I can improve the performance of my application, I want to load it faster,
or I want to reduce some rerenders and etc.
You can ask also if you implement some search functionality or any other, some authentication,
please give me few ideas or ways how I can do it in my application.
You can also get help with some coding tasks, you can ask how to implement search and
functionality for this component, for you, for example, you can ask how to handle correctly
some key events for buttons or for different components, so for example if you use any
library, you can also ask help how to use the API as a library or how to build the button
or some list or some other component, so now let's get back to our videos to the code
and I will show you the interface of the ask mode. Normally it is just what you need
to choose the ask mode and type some question, for example, let's open the calculator
and you can ask how I can, for example, implement the history of functionality, it means
that when you do the calculations, it will remember every operation in a history, so how
I can add history, functionality, to calculator, to store every operation, and for example
give me two ideas how I can implement it, or it can be implemented, let's see what it
will provide, so you see okay, it provides some text, the history array property to the
class, as you see here, and it also for the suggest to do in every method I guess, in every
method, adjust the value with the current value, just a text to the history, on every
action we do, the next implementation idea is okay, it's a bit bigger like we can do the
operation names, the input values, the previous value, the result, and also the timestamp
when it was done, for example, if you like it you can implement this idea like for every
thing, for every method, let's stick with first ideas much easier, and for example, instead
of copy paste and you can click on this button, maybe she will apply it ever seen, and
you see it just did it for every method, and now you see the div, you see the div, the
difference between previous and new implementation, what you can do, you can switch between
all the lines where it was implemented, you can accept it one by one, for example, you
can keep everything, or you can just undo, like, to back all these changes, I will keep
everything, so and this is how you normally can use, as much, for example, you can also
ask about some terminal commands, like, if you open the terminal and you can ask, let's
remove one of them, terminal, and I can ask, okay, oh, I can list all the files in this
folder. For example, it will provide you the command, and you can immediately start this
command from a chat, you can click and start it into terminal, and now you can press enter
and see the result, and for example, same you can do with this command and you see like
it in more detail way, so this is how you can use ask mode and see you in the next question
where we will go through the edit mode.